BRIAN C. BAKER

22157 Metamora Lane Beverly Hills, MI 48025 Phone: 248.417.2929 brianbaker.design@yahoo.com

I have 35 years' experience as a professional Automobile Designer, Consultant to Industry, Expert Witness and globally recognized speaker on Design history and the future. For three decades I've instructed Art, Design and the business of Design to International designers. As a President of the Society of Automotive Historians, I pursue my lifelong study of Design, Inspiring others to understand the history and potential future of their world.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

AUTOARCHEOLOGY LLC; INTERNATIONAL DESIGN CONSULTING: Founder 2009

Multiple International OEM clients; Consultant & Design expert witness Antique Automobile Club of America Museum: Hershey, PA, National Development

Mecum Classic Car Auctions, Walworth, WI Media relations consultant

Motorsports Hall of Fame Museum of America Exhibit Design

ASC: AMERICAN SPECIALITY CARS; Technical Center, Warren MI

Vice-Président, Design & Marketing

2014 - 2015

Directed OEM relationships; Mercedes Benz Commercial: Executive over a 25 member creation team through the Design, Fabrication & Prototyping for Pepsico & Entegra Luxury Motor Coaches.

GENERAL MOTORS CORPORATION Technical & Design Center, Warren, MI 1984 - 2009

Sr. Design Manager, Corporate Brand Character Studio 1996 – 1998

I co-created this pioneering, internal "**Design Think Tank**" an all digital studio Created "*Speed Vision*", a design acceleration methodology

Sr. Designer: Chevrolet SSR, Pontiac GTO, Cadillac Concepts, and more...

U.S. Automotive Patent holder: (# 6,347,828) Chevrolet SSR, retractable hard top

Lead Designer for : Cadillac, Chevrolet, Saturn and Advanced design studios

Opel AG Design Studios Germany, International Service Personnel assignment 1987-1988

DESIGNER, EDUCATOR & SPEAKER

SOCIETY OF AUTOMOTIVE HISTORIANS, President, Detroit Leland Chapter Since 2017

THE EYE, THE BRAIN AND THE AUTO; AUTONOMOUS VEHICLE CONFERENCE, Detroit 2018

AMERICAN CULTURAL IMMERSION CONFERENCE Keynote Speaker, TOKYO, JAPAN 2018

IQPC ADVANCED LIGHTING STRATEGIES CONFERENCE, Chairman, Detroit 2018

ITB Futures keynote speaker: Millennials 2035 studies, Novi MI 2016

INDIA AUTOMOTIVE SUMMIT; Keynote Speaker, PUNE, INDIA 2014

OEM & TIER ONE; Confidential Design Consultant: S. Korea, Japan & China Since 2014

THE HENRY FORD MUSEUM Historical Presenter 2016

Tesla, Inc. v. Nikola Corporation
US Patent 10,077,084
Tesla Ex. 1017

LAWRENCE TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, SCHOOL OF DESIGN, Southfield MI 2010-present History of Modern Industrial / Vehicle Design: development of motorized vehicle & the future **DESIGN HISTORIAN & AUTHOR** 2002-present Lead the creation & Art Direction of; DRIVING STYLE; The first century of GM Design. P.2008 COLLEGE FOR CREATIVE STUDIES, Detroit, MI History of Modern Design; The Industrial Revolution to today and in the future 2007- present Presenting cultural, world events and the history of Industrial manufacturing and design to A survey of; products, popular culture, architecture and lifestyles; 1850 to the future. Design/ Art Studio Instructor. Freshman & Sophomore 3-D design studios Senior Industrial Design Portfolio Instructor CONTINUING EDUCATION DEPARTMENT & COMMUNITY ARTS PARTNERSHIPS CCS @PARC intro to auto design instructor Since 2017 Pre College Instructor; Intro to Design program for international students 2012-present Henry Ford Academy (New Center Campus) Intro to Design 2012-2013 THE UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN / CCS partnership: Female vehicle concepts for 2035 2014 Lead a research study with rural and urban millennial females anticipate they will want in their vehicles as they become parents. 20 High School age students CLEVELAND INSTITUTE OF THE ARTS, COLLEGE OF DESIGN 2012-2014 FCA sponsored Design Studio instructor. Corporate sponsored project Lear Corporation; High School, Intro to vehicle design program. 25 students 2013 Vehicle Concepts for the mid 21st Century **General Motors Design International Education Manager** 2001-2007 Global university summer internship program for 24 designers from 4 continents WAYNE STATE UNIVERSITY, Detroit, MI 1988-1990 Adjunct Professor; School of Industrial Design DISCOVERY CHANNEL, Future Car TV Series 2006-2008 **Television concept & production** Assistant Producer for the "Future Car" TV program 1992 INDY CAR RACING, Mann Motorsports Indianapolis, IN Media and graphic materials designer, Top 10 finish in the Indianapolis 500

EDUCATION

ART CENTER COLLEGE OF DESIGN, Pasadena, CA Bachelor of Science with Honors 1980-1984

COLLEGE FOR CREATIVE STUDIES, Detroit, MI 1979-1980 INDIANA UNIVERSITY, Indianapolis, IN 1978-1979

AWARDS & PRESENTATIONS and NETWORK BROADCASTS

ESPN Design Historian for "Harley Earl and NASCAR" TV program

Book Publishers Association; Bronze medal <u>Driving Style: GM designs first century 2008</u>

2000 NA International Auto Show "Most Significant Concept" Lead designer, Chevrolet SSR

Thank you for your consideration. Brian C. Baker (248) 417-2929